<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Udit Narayan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Udit Narayan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Different Approach to Quadratic Equations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/quadratic_equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/quadratic_equation/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss a cool and innovative approach to quadratic equations. I&amp;rsquo;m sure all of you are familiar with the dreadful quadratic equation. I&amp;rsquo;m sure most of you remember it as well but of course, it&amp;rsquo;s a pain in the arse. Have you ever wished there was an easier way without all the memorisation? Well, your wish has come true!
Consider a quadratic equation :
$$ x^2 + ax + b = 0$$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chinese Remainder Theorem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/chinese_remainder_theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/chinese_remainder_theorem/</guid>
      <description>This is a famous theorem in elementary number theory which is suited to answer a specific type of question whose first appearance was seen in Chinese literature, and hence the name Chinese Remainder Theorem. The question asks - &amp;ldquo;Find the positive integers which give remainders \(a_1, a_2, a_3, a_4\) when divided by \(n_1, n_2, n_3, n_4\) respectively.&amp;rdquo; We first derive the mathematical tools required to tackle the problem.
Linear Congruences As the name suggests, we deal with congruences such as \(ax \equiv b \ (mod \ n) \).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Math behind a Calendar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/calendar/</guid>
      <description>Backstory We all know that the earth takes 365 days to complete one revolution around the sun&amp;hellip;or does it? Well, not quite. It takes approximately 365.2422 days. The early Julian Calendar (introduced by Julius Caesar) rounded off the decimal to one-fourths which accumulated to a day once every four years. Hence a day was added to every year (in February as I&amp;rsquo;m sure you know) once in four years. This year was termed a leap year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Pigeonhole Principle - 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/php2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/php2/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss a couple examples where Pigeonhole principle is employed. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know what the Pigeonhole principle is, you can read my post on it. Here is the link.
The Friendship Theorem Among six people, there are always three who know each other or three who are complete strangers.
How can one establish such a statement using mathematics? It almost sounds preposterous! Here we use another concept well known to us but appears to be unrelated - Geometry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pigeonhole Principle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/php1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/php1/</guid>
      <description>The Pigeonhole Principle (or the Box Principle) looks obvious and straightforward on first glance but it has a very widespread application. It shows itself in the most unexpected of places and the proofs involving it are striking examples of mathematical elegance.
So what is this principle? In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll write about a version of this principle which I find more intuitive. Here you have a certain number of pigeons which you must place inside a certain number of holes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theorem in Number Theory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/number_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/number_theory/</guid>
      <description>For positive integers \(a,b\) where \(gcd(a,b) = 1\), the equation \(ax + by = n\) always has a solution in positive \(x,y\) for all \(n \geq ab\) Proof
Since \(gcd(a,b) = 1\), by the theory of linear Diophantine equations, we know that there always exists solutions (infinitely many of them) for \(ax + by = n\). However we are only interested in the ones where both \(x\) and \(y\) are positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>High school student from Vizag, India who is very interested in Mathematics. On this blog, I will share elegant math problems and proofs. Currently I am interested in Number theory, Functions and Polynomials. I also make telegram bots. You can check them out here :  csgo-bot maki-management-bot  Site made using Hugo</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>